aoi hoshi ni senritsu ga hashiru
a
o
i
ho
shi
ni
se
n
ri
tsu
ga
ha
shi
ru
A shudder runs over the blue planet
푸른 지구에 전율이 흐른다
kuroi arashi chikazuku toki
ku
ro
i
a
ra
shi
chi
ka
zu
ku
to
ki
It's the time the dark storm approaches
검은 폭풍이 닥쳐오는 순간
kokoro no oku de mezameru HERO
ko
ro
no
o
ku
de
me
za
ru
HE
RO
It's as if a hero is awakening on the inside
마음 속의 눈을 뜬 영웅들이여
tobitatsu no da furimukazu ni
to
bi
ta
tsu
no
da
fu
ri
mu
ka
zu
ni
Fly away and don't look back!
뒤돌아보지 말고 날아가라
DAGWON kagayake DAGWON
DA
G
WON
ka
ga
ya
ke
DA
G
WON
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
Brave Command Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
Dagwon... Shine on!! Dagwon!
다그온 빛나라!! 다그온
heiwa mamoru namae sa
he
i
wa
ma
mo
ru
na
ma
e
sa
The name that protects the peace
평화를 지키는 이름이다
DAGWON oretachi DAGWON
DA
G
WON
o
re
ta
chi
DA
G
WON
Dagwon! We are Dagwon!
다그온 우리는 다그온
yume wa zettai watasanai
yu
me
wa
ze
t
ta
i
wa
ta
sa
na
i
We will never hand over our dream
꿈은 절대로 넘겨줄 수 없다
afureru yuuki te ni shitai nara
a
fu
re
ru
yu
u
ki
te
ni
shi
ta
i
na
ra
To grab the overflowing courage
넘쳐흐르는 용기를 거머쥐고 싶다면
tsuyoku tsuyoku yuujou shinjiru koto sa
tsu
yo
ku
tsu
yo
ku
yu
u
jo
shi
n
ji
ru
ko
to
sa
We believe in our friendship firmly
우리 우정을 굳게 믿는 거다
kizutsuku koto mo osore wa shinai
ki
zu
tsu
ku
ko
to
mo
o
so
re
wa
shi
na
i
We are not afraid of getting hurt
상처입는 것도 두렵지 않아
mugendai no mirai wo egaku sono tame ni
mu
ge
n
da
i
no
mi
ra
i
wo
e
ga
ku
so
no
ta
me
ni
In order to reach that infinite future!
무한대의 미래를 그려내기 위해서라면
Game Over
게임 오버
Space Ghost Chaos Seijin
Appears
우주 유령 카오스 성인 등장
So... 9:12 AM, it stopped.
그러니까… 오전 9시 12분, 멈춰섰다
Huh?
어레?
-I lost him.
-Do you need to talk with me?
-놓쳐버렸다
-내게 무슨 볼일이지?
Why are you following my back?
왜 내 뒤를 쫓는거지?
That's... uh...
그건… 그…
That's a secret between me and my client!
의뢰인의 비밀이야!
A client?
의뢰인?
I see!
과연!
Who the heck is it?!
누구냐, 이자식!
Ehehe, this is, um... something...
아하하;; 아니, 이건 말야… 그, 뭐랄까…
I guess he's your client.
저녀석이 네 의뢰인이지?
He told me he'll get Dagwon's autographs for me...
다그온의 사진과 사인을 받아다 준다고 해서
-Hey, Ryu!
-What?
-이봐, 류!
-뭐지?
Look at that! There!
저기 봐, 저거!
Shadow Ryu!
섀도우 류!
Wait for me!
잠깐 기다려!
Hey! Why did you leave me?!
이봐! 왜 날 두고 가는거야?!
It's you who's late.
네가 늦은 것 뿐이잖아
What?!
뭐야?!
Shadow Kunai!
섀도우 쿠나이!
Shoulder Burn!
숄더 번!
Go for it, Dagwon!
힘내라, 다그온!
Fire Bird Attack!
파이어 버드 어택!
Why would dinosaurs' bones move?
공룡 뼈가 대체 왜?
Y- you bastard!
이, 이자식이!
You're not getting away!
안 놓친다!
Preparing
준비중
Seems that we're invited by the alien.
아무래도 우주인에게 초대받은 모양이구만
Action? Or shooting?
액션? 아니면 슈팅?
What's this?
뭐지?
Arcade game. Which of these are you good at?
게임 말야, 뭘 잘하냐?
Not interested.
흥미 없어
I guess it's not here. Let's go.
여기엔 없는 것 같군, 가자
I'll show my skill next time!
다음번에 내 실력을 보여줄게
En.
엔
Why?
왜그래?
Why did you follow me this morning?
왜 아침에 날 미행했지?
Because you were different from others. You're mysterious, and I'm curious.
다른 녀석들과는 달라서 말이지
넌 정체 불명이라 호기심이 생겼거든
I do not like to be interfered by other people.
난 다른 사람에게 간섭받는걸 싫어해
But as the leader of Dagwon, I have rights to know about you.
하지만 난 다그온의 리더로서 너에 대해 알 권리가 있어
Leader?
리더?
Since when you became a leader?
네가 언제부터 리더가 됐지?
Wait! You can at least tell me about your hobby, specialty, or something you like!
기다리라니까! 하다못해 취미나 특기라든가 좋아하는 거라든지 말야
I do not have a hobby or specialty.
취미도 특기도 없어
-Eating breakfast while dozing.
-What?
-졸면서 아침밥 먹기였던가?
-뭐?
My specialty!
내 특기
Shut up and find the alien.
입 다물고 우주인이나 찾아
It finally appeared.
이제서야 납시셨나
This is totally awesome! It's an unprecedented spiritual phenomenon!
굉장해! 굉장해! 이거, 전대미문(前代未聞)의 심령현상이야
Did you take something, Gaku?
뭔가 찍혔니, 가쿠?
Nothing special.
그다지…
A spiritual picture can be only taken in the probability of 0.01%. Keep taking the pictures!
심령사진은 1/10000장의 확률이야 쉴틈없이 셔터 누르라구
I know! Hmph...
알았다구! 정말…
It seems that that dinosaur skeleton was being controlled by a light fallen from the sky that Gaku told me about.
공룡 뼈는, 아무래도 가쿠가 봤다고 하는 하늘에서 떨어진 빛에 조종되고 있었던 것 같아
So you're saying that light is the alien from Sargasso?
그 빛이 사르갓소의 우주인이라는 거지?
Right.
그래
How was it?
어떻게 됐어?
No good! En and Ryu are not responding!
틀렸어요! 엔과 류의 응답이 없습니다!
What?!
뭐야?!
Look and learn. A duel in the underworld planet. It's a virtual reality game on a roll nowadays.
자 봐. 마계 혹성의 결투 요즘 잘 나가는 체감(體感) 게임이야
Virtual reality?
체감 게임?
In this game, only this will cut them.
게임이라서 말야
이녀석으로 밖에는 벨 수 없어
And then, when we take down the boss monster in that rock mountain, we clear the game.
그리고 저 바위산에 사는 보스 캐릭터를 쓰러뜨리면 게임 클리어
What are you going to do? Play a bit?
어떻게 할래? 좀 놀아볼까?
Hey, is this a game too?
이봐, 이것도 게임인가?
No, this is...
아니, 이건…
Feh! What's this this time?!
쳇! 이번엔 뭐냐?!
This guys are not virtual images!
이녀석들, 입체영상이… 아니야!
Fire Knuckle!
파이어 너클!
Overhead Shuriken!
오버 헤드 수리검!
Shuriken Dropkick!
수리검 내려차기!
What the heck is going on?!
대체 어떻게 된거야?!
Fire Stratus!
파이어 스투라투스!
Hmph, it didn't work?
쳇! 역시 무리군
Are we in the world of game, or the real world?
여긴 게임의 세계일까, 아니면 현실일까?
-We're facing an alien.
-Huh?
-우주인이다
-음?
Think about it.
생각해봐
A dinosaur skeleton, a doll, and now, a world of game.
공룡 뼈, 인형, 그리고 이번엔 게임의 세계
The alien is giving them lives.
모두 우주인이 생명을 불어넣고 있는거야
-I see! Then the escape will be simple!
-What?
-그렇군! 그럼 탈출은 간단하겠구만
-뭐야?
We just have to clear the game!
게임을 클리어하면 되는 거라구!
I see.
과연…
- You do pretty well!
-Hmph, you too.
-제법 하는데!
-훗, 너도다
Where? Where are them? En, Ryu!
어디지? 어디에 있는 거야? 엔! 류!
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
Original Korean Subtitles by Jaebari (재바리)
Translated to English by Subdivers
Checked by Great Exkaiser103
자막 원본(번역): 재바리
수정: Subdivers
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
VR Dome
Alright! We're breaking through the enemy line and fight against the boss monster!
좋아! 이대로 적진으로 쳐들어가서 단숨에 보스 캐릭터와 승부한다!
Wh- what's this?!
어, 어떻게 된 거지?!
Guard Hawk!
가드 호크!
-What's this guy?!
-This is bad! A mini boss!
-뭐지, 이녀석은?!
-위험해! 중간보스야!
What the-?!
뭐지?!
They transformed?
변형하다니?!
You guys!
너희들!
Duck!
위험해!
En!
엔!
I'm going! Take me with you!
나도 간다! 날 데려가라구!
What do you think you can do now?
지금의 네가 뭘 할 수 있을 것 같나?
What did you say?!
뭐라고?! 크윽!
You'll end up holding my back with that body. Leave the rest to me.
그 몸으론 발목을 잡을 뿐이야 뒤는 내게 맡겨라
You... can you determine the gender of chicks?
너… 병아리의 암수를 판별할 수 있어?
What?
뭐?
-Gender of chicks.
-What about that?
-병아리의 암수 판별 말이야
-그게 뭐 어쨌다는 거냐?
It's my specialty.
내… 특기야
-What's so funny!
-It's a damn uncool specialty!
뭐가 웃기지?! 아니, 유별난 특기라서 말야
Hey, Ryu!
-이봐, 류!
-음?
Is it difficult? Determining the chicks' gender.
가르쳐 줄래? 병아리 판별
Maybe. I'll let you know when we get out of here.
그래, 여길 탈출하면 가르쳐 주지
-Alright, that's a promise!
-Sure.
-좋아, 약속이다!
-응!
You must be the boss!
네녀석이 보스구나!
A match!
승부다!
You've trapped into my Shadow Ninja Technique!
걸렸구나, 내 섀도우 인법(忍法)
Shadow Duplication!
그림자 분신(影分身)!
Here I go!
간다!
Big Spiral Whirlwind Slash!
대회전 검풍참!
Chest!
슛!
A- again?!
또, 또냐?!
No way! That alien bastard!
또냐, 우주인 녀석!
Was it sticking itself to this building?!
이 건물에 이렇게 붙어 있었던 건가?!
This is bad. It's not going to break!
안돼겠어! 부서질 기미가 보이질 않아
-Alright! Me too!
-Hey! You shouldn't do that by yourself!
-좋아! 나도!
-이봐, 그 몸으론 무리야
Doing it myself wouldn't work, but we don't know if we do together.
혼자선 무리여도 둘이라면 또 모르잖아?
I see, leader.
그렇군, 리더
-Let's do this!
-Roger!
-류!
-오우!
-Fire Knuckle!
-Shadow Kunai!
파이어 너클!
섀도우 쿠나이!
Double Attack!
더블 어택!
You two were safe after all!
두사람 모두 무사했구나!
Alright, time for Merging Fusion!
좋아, 융합합체다!
Merging Fusion!
융합합체
(融合合體)
Dag Turbo!
다그 터보
Merging Fusion!
융합합체
(融合合體)
Dag Armor!
다그 아머
Merging Fusion!
융합합체
(融合合體)
Dag Wing!
다그 윙
Blizzard Typhoon!
블리자드 타이푼!
Final Buster!
파이널 버스터!
Break Wheel!
브레이크 호일!
Did we do it?
해치웠나?!
In this rate... Shadow Jet, take off!
이대로는… 섀도우 제트 발진!
No!
안돼!
En!
엔!
Merging Fusion!
융합합체
(融合合體)
Dag Shadow!
다그 섀도우
What the-?!
아, 아니?!
This is... Is this Merging Fusion?!
이건… 설마, 융합합체?!
Futile!
쓸데없는 짓을!
It's my turn now!
이번엔 이쪽에서 간다!
Sky! Earth! Human!
천(天)! 지(地)! 인(人)!
Gather the three principle into one!
3가지의 이치(理)를 하나로 모아!
This is Dag Shadow! Absolute Light Speed Sword!
이것이 다그 섀도우!
절대 광속검!
Shadow Dragon!
섀도우 드래곤!
Dragon Plasma Burn!
드래곤 플라즈마 번!
Hey!
어이~
You did it! That's one additional specialty!
해냈구만! 이걸로 특기가 하나 더 늘었군
As now all of us can perform Merging Fusion, no matter what alien comes, we're not afraid them!
전원이 융합합체를 할 수 있게 되었으니까 말야 더이상 그 어떤 우주인이라도 두렵지 않아!
Ryu!
류!
Hey! Hang in there, Ryu!
이봐! 정신차리라구! 류!
Ryu!
류!
D- don't worry. It's alright now.
괘, 괜찮아… 걱정하지마
It vanished.
녀석은 소멸했어
It was its last struggle.
훗… 최후의 발버둥이었어…
Ryu!
류!
The sun suddenly called me
태양이 갑작스레 나를 불러내서
taiyou ga fui ni ore wo izanau
To come to the blue sea
푸르게 비치는 바다로 만나러 갔지
aoku sukitooru umi ni ai ni kita
The ripples are coming and going
밀려왔다 돌아가는 잔물결
yosete wa kaesu sazanami
tomaru koto nai MELODY
An endless melody
멈추지 않는 멜로디
sono sugata towa ni tsunagu you ni
To keep that shape for eternity
그 모습을 영원히 유지할 수 있도록
I'll follow the fate of the dream
꿈의 행방을 뒤쫓아 갈 거야
oikakete yuku yo yume no yukue
tooku kirameita
Sparkling far away
멀리서 반짝이던
kaze no naka no PRISM
A Prism in the Wind
바람 속의 프리즘
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
Preview for Next Episode
용자지령
다그온
차회예고
We found something awesome!
엄청난 걸 발견했어!
Our base, Dag Base, was hidden in the mountain behind our school!
학교 뒷산에 숨겨져 있던 우리들의 기지, 다그 베이스!
At that time, an enemy has appeared in the village.
그 때 마을에 적이 나타났어
They are prison guards robots of Sargasso the space prison!
우주감옥 사르갓소의 간수 로봇들이야!
It's not right. They must be the robots made by Brave Seijin...
분명히 브레이브 성인이 만든 로봇일텐데…
Who is controlling these guys?!
이녀석들을 뒤에서 조종하는 놈은 누구냐!?
Next time on Yuusha Shirei Dagwon! The Mystery of Sargasso
다음회 용자지령 다그온
사르갓소의 수수께끼
Ryu, you're a mystery too!
류! 너도 수수께끼닷!
The Mystery of Sargasso
사르갓소의 수수께끼